# NORMAN LO

**LinkedIn:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/norman-data-economist

GitHub: https://github.com/NormanLo4319

Website: https://normanlo4319.github.io/Norman Lo Web

Phone: (415) 706-8788

**Address:** San Francisco, CA 94107 **E-mail:** lokmannorman@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Data scientist with 6+ years of experience in academic research, data management, building predictive models, business system analysis, and data mining algorithms for delivering insights to complex problems. Strong math background and experience using different programming languages, such as Javascript, Python, R, Stata, Spark, and SQL. Certified Tableau desktop specialist who brings technical background knowledge to enhance decision-making and achieve company goals.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: Python, R, Stata, SQL, noSQL, VBA, Javascript, HTML, CSS

Data Manipulation & Visualization: pandas, matplotlib, seaborn, Tableau, Plotly, D3, ggplot2, numpy, scipy

Database: mySQL, postgeSQL, mongoDB, SQLAlchemy

Other: Git, Flask, command line, machine learning, big data analysis, TensorFlow, Spark, Scikit-Learn, AWS, BI

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Data Scientist, CoStar Group

2022 – present

- Conduct independent and creative quantitative research applied towards the evaluation and improvement of CRE models, data series and estimations
- Perform econometric-based forecasting and quantitative analysis
- Document models and analytic products and tools for external and internal clients
- Implement data mining techniques to leverage databases for use in a variety of products and tools

Adjunct Faculty, DVC, SFSU, USF, CCSF, St Mary's College, Metro. State University

2015 – present

- Teach both undergraduate and graduate level Economics, Data Mining, and Business Statistics courses
- Guide graduate and undergraduate students to develop data-driven research projects

Data Scientist Lecturer, Flatiron School

2021 - 2022

- Teach data science curriculum in synchronous online format
- Maintain GitHub lecture repository and update lecture notebook files periodically
- Guide students developing the capstone project and provide business application suggestions

Data Scientist, Code with Corgis

2019 - 2021

- Support product and leadership teams with insights gained from analyzing company data
- Utilize machine learning models and data mining techniques to forecast company sales of new products
- Communicate clearly and effectively to cross functional partners of varying technical levels

## **PROJECTS**

## World Happiness Project (Developer for Education Institution) | Backend Git Live | Dashboard Git

- Built a back-end API with SQLAlchemy and Flask for data request.
- Created a front-end data product to request data from the API and provided visualizations for clients.
- Demonstrated a statistically significant correlation between happiness and income inequality across 156 countries.

# Public Health Scores & Yelp Customer-Based Rating (Independent Research) | Live

- Analyzed the restaurants' public health score and Yelp customer-based rating in San Francisco.
- Pulled and stored data from Yelp API and SFDPH on over 2000 restaurants into SQL database.
- Food environment only explained 2.33% of the health outcomes at the county level.

#### **EDUCATION**

Bootcamp Certificate: U.C. Berkeley Extension, San Francisco

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programing skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, JavaScript, SQL

Databases, Tableau, Big Data, and Machine Learning.

**M.A. in Economics:** San Francisco State University, San Francisco **B.A. in Economics:** San Francisco State University, San Francisco